Now that you know how to gather data,
والآن بعد أن تعرفت على كيفية جمع البيانات،
you're going to master assessing it.
يمكنك الانتقال إلى تقييمها.
Assessing your data is the second step in the data wrangling process.
ويعد تقييم البيانات الخيار الثاني في عملية تعارض البيانات.
When assessing, you're like a detective at work.
عند التقييم، تبدو مثل محقق في العمل.
Inspecting your data set for two things: Data quality issues and lack of tidiness.
فحص مجموعة البيانات الخاصة بك لأمرين: مشكلات في جودة البيانات وعدم الترتيب.
Data that has quality issues has issues with content like missing,
تحتوي البيانات التي تتضمن مشكلات في الجودة على مشكلات في المحتوى مثل
duplicate or incorrect data.
البيانات المفقودة أو المكررة أو غير الصحيحة.
This is called dirty data.
ويطلق على هذا اسم البيانات المهملة.
An untidy or messy data has specific structural issues.
البيانات غير المنتظمة أو غير المرتبة لها مشكلات هيكلية محددة.
These structural issues slow you down when cleaning and analyzing,
تبطئك هذه المشكلات الهيكلية عند تنظيف البيانات وتحليلها،
visualizing or modeling your data later.
أو تصورها أو نمذجتها في وقت لاحق.
You can search for these issues in two ways: Visually,
يمكنك البحث عن هذه المشكلات بطريقتين: بصريًا،
with a simple scroll and programmatically using code.
من خلال تمرير بسيط وبرمجيًا باستخدام التعليمات البرمجية.
And when you detect an issue,
وعندما تكتشف مشكلة،
you document it to make cleaning easier.
تقوم بتوثيقها لتسهيل المسح.
In this lesson, you will assess a pre-gathered data
في هذا الدرس، ستقوم بتقييم مجموعة بيانات مجمعة مسبقًا
set that's full of issues and you're going to find all of them.
ومليئة بالمشكلات وستجدها كلها.
Some visually and others using the functions in Python's Pandas library.
بعض العناصر البصرية وغيرها باستخدام الدوال الموجودة في مكتبة Pandas التابعة لـ Python.
At the end of the lesson, we'll flash forward to analysis
في نهاية الدرس، سنتقدم نحو التحليل
and visualization where you'll see how your assessments were vital.
والتحليل المرئي حيث سترى كيف كانت تقييماتك حيوية.
You're going to leave this lesson with an eagle eye for
ستترك هذا الدرس بملاحظة دقيقة
unclean data and there's a lot of it in the world.
عن بيانات غير نظيفة وهناك الكثير منها في العالم.